Maybe I could hold your hand? And together we can understand...
Don't Hug Me I'm Scared 3 is a horror, fantasy,
animation film directed by Becky Sloan.
During a chicken picnic, Yellow Guy gets upset
after Green Bird kills a butterfly.
Yellow Guy then meets a butterfly that takes him on a
journey to discover his concept of love.
Yellow Guy / Duck Guy / Additional Characters (voice), played by Baker Terry.
Additional Voices (voice), played by Becky Sloan.
Red Guy / Additional Voices (voice), played by Joseph Pelling.
Shrignold / Additional Voices (voice), played by Royngtt.
Don't Hug Me I'm Scared is a British surrealist adult puppet musical comedy horror web series created by Becky Sloan and
Joe Pelling that consists of six short episodes released on YouTube between 29 July 2011 and 19 June 2016.
It is notable for blending surrealism and dark comedy with
psychological horror and musical elements.
Its production is diverse, combining puppetry and live action with styles of animation including stop
motion, traditional animation, flash animation, claymation, and computer animation.
A sequel television series, also consisting of six episodes, was
released on All 4 and Channel 4 on 23 September 2022.
Each episode of the series starts like a typical children's programme, consisting of
anthropomorphic puppets akin to those featured in Sesame Street or The Muppets.
The series parodies and satirises these programmes by juxtaposing its inhabitants and their childlike, colourful environment against disturbing themes; each episode develops a plot twist that incorporates psychological
horror, surreal imagery, dark comedy, extreme graphic violence, and existentialism, before returning the traumatised characters to their original situation with an altered outlook as a result of their experience.
The six episodes of the web series explore creativity, time, love, technology, food, and dreams; the
television series touches on jobs, death, family, friendship, transport, and electricity.
Both have received widespread critical acclaim for their story, production design,
psychological horror, humour, hidden themes, lore, and characters.
The film explores themes of musical, surrealism,
love, woman director, puppet film.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.